[Music]
we're lucky to have
anita joining us today anita comes with
us with a wealth of experience across
financial services
working in kpmg for a number of years uh
currently
the chief risk officer for prudential
she's also just recently
the winner of the top 50 women in
islamic business and finance
award first question anita how do you
empower
others around you and how do you set the
tone in your division
i think the behaviors and culture of an
organization
is a direct reflection of the
leadership style of the leaders in the
organization
and for me empowerment um is basically
about uh trust and delegation
so uh and it's also about setting up
front
you know what are your expectations from
your team members
and setting the objectives upfront so
that
they are aware of their responsibilities
you may notice it's an asian phenomenon
where people tend to be very polite so
you know i actively encourage my team to
speak out and voice your opinions
um as it's really about two-way
communication
and for me personally it's also
my role to drive actions and you know
foster team work
the other thing which i feel is really
critical is
communication and providing that in a
timely basis
so i take the opportunity to try and
communicate the why you know as famously
mentioned by simon sinek
i'm really excited that we've just
recently launched an app called
tell me and the app has been rolled out
to all levels of staff
to allow them to be able to provide
direct feedback in real time
there are a lot of challenges for people
what do you think the biggest challenge
for the next generation of women is
there are huge opportunities for the
current generation of women
and especially with the covet 19 crisis
we saw many leaders such as prime
minister jacinda arden
who demonstrated that it was possible to
be a strong
yet empathetic leader but having said
that i think women still face a number
of challenges
there's conflict between work life where
society still tends to place an
expectation that women do
more of the heavy lifting at work as
well as at home
and that tends to put a little bit more
pressure on them
how i respond to that as a mother and as
a leader
and i'm a mother of two boys so i keep
encouraging my boys and advising them
that responsibility at home is equally
shared between both
men and women and i think you know
that's
a message that we women leaders can
impart to our families
secondly i think women face unequal
treatment when it comes to
opportunities that's an area where
we try very much to have diversity and
inclusion
as an agenda next question traits
of leaders you admire either male or
female
what sort of resonates and sticks with
you the first thing that comes to my
mind is authenticity
and i think increasingly leadership is
really about being true to yourself and
being authentic
and i've had the privilege of working
with
many such leaders in the course of my
career
they have a clear vision and they have a
strong set of values
and they're also people who are willing
to mentor
and lift others along the way
they you know tend to provide credit
when it's due
at the same time being highly
professional as well
and i also admire leaders who have the
courage of their convictions
and they're willing to speak up even if
it may not be the popular choice to do
so
i think the other thing that's important
is having a sense of humor
to me because i think that helps you to
create a bond with your team members
conversely i think i also have no time
for
leaders who believe they need to sort of
run others down in order
in order to get ahead what are some of
the leadership lessons you've taken away
along your journey from them personally
my values have sort of dictated the
organizations that i've worked with
and when you have a strong set of values
and guiding principles
i think it's easier to make decisions
and
paying attention to details is a big one
for me as well
because as they say the devil is in the
details
i think the other thing is always be
willing to impart your knowledge
so i enjoy mentoring other women
as well as men in their career journey
it's important to be
empathetic as this really allows you to
create
you know this bond of trust with your
people and
i'm also a firm believer that it's good
to surround yourself
and bring on board people with very
diverse views
because they can then bring a fresh
perspective and they can challenge you
rather than being surrounded by people
who think alike lastly i think
as a leader it's always important that
we remain grounded
and we practice humility next question
your advice or some strategies you have
for women who are trying to get more
prominent roles or leadership roles in
historically male dominated
either job functions or industries
progress starts with awareness right and
in recent years we've seen and read
about women in the media who played
prominent roles in
traditionally male dominated industries
and
that that helps to create awareness and
at the same time it helps to inspire
other women hopefully
to pursue similar careers the um
i think the second important factor
would be
to build a support system and build
a network and you know identify allies
as you progress in the organization
which is something men are generally
better at and i think women
can sort of take a leap from that
thirdly i think it's about
removing this unconscious bias that we
tend to have
when i was at kpmg and right now at
prudential bsn
we we certainly don't lack women in the
workplace
but what i observe is that as they get
higher in the organization
women tend to drop out or opt out of the
workplace due to muslim countries buyers
and
the fact that you know they are the ones
who are expected to
perhaps give up their careers in order
to focus on their families
so men on the other hand don't have such
pressure
and i think if more and more
organizations are able to address that
that will certainly help women in a long
way
next question if i were a brand i would
be
i would say amazon and um
it's really interesting to me that
what started off as an online platform
primarily selling books
has now evolved to a one-stop
shop i would say you know for literally
any
and every imaginable good and it's truly
inspiring to see the way
how jeff resource built up the brand
and built up the business he of course
you know brought in people again with
very diverse backgrounds
and i sort of see that
somewhat related to my own personal and
professional journey
what are some ways that you've gained
more confidence in yourself
i think for me what's worked is uh
really taking risks
and stepping out of my comfort zone i
keep going back to taking risks which
may sound unusual coming from a cro
but it's really all about calculated
risks
as an example i you know was working in
kpmg as
a partner in a big four firm and i
really enjoyed that role
but when i had this opportunity come up
to join through bsn
i i took the role as i really wanted to
step out of my comfort zone
and to challenge and to sort of continue
continuously learn new things
prior to that i worked in the stem
industry
and um i started my life as a scientist
but along the way i realized that it's
not really my cup of tea
you know i really enjoyed working with
people much more
um cancer switch to consulting and
financial services
so i think each of these experiences
have been
really uh and truly invaluable
and you know that's probably uh to some
extent my leadership style as well
the other way that i sort of build
confidence is really
through speaking at conferences or
publishing thought leadership
firstly i enjoy that connection with
people but at the same time that helps
me build confidence as well
and the other thing i think most of all
is having a sense
of purpose and passion
in whatever you do i'm a huge advocate
that you must be passionate about what
you do
what energizes you i enjoy sitting down
with my team and brainstorming
new ideas solutions to existing
problems or issues that we have and
i i enjoy working on different projects
and
which allows me to collaborate with
different teams
but mostly i think the work that we do
here and realizing that it plays
a key role in the lives of our customers
in a way where they were able to be
there for them in their times of need
that really you know energizes me at
home
or personally it's really about spending
time with my family
and friends i love exercising so
it's about going to the gym or you know
going for an early morning run
that that really puts me in the right
frame of mind in the morning
it's also spending time with my boys
watching a really
you know funny movie and um you know
generally
that's that's the sort of way that i uh
de-stress
the first woman you looked up to and why
was it her and what was
the the real value you took from it my
novel would be my mom
my mom came from a traditional indian
background
and she was a homemaker but she was also
someone who had a
clear sense of responsibility and
independence
and from her i learned that you know i
could go out there and achieve whatever
i set my mind on
if i were to choose someone in the
corporate field
it would be indra nui who was the former
chairman and ceo of pepsico with
her i was hugely inspired by her story
about
how she moved to the u.s and you know
she met challengers headlong
she became the ceo of a top 500
company and the sort of decisions
that she made every step of the way and
i think what really resonated with me
was she came across as being a fairly
grounded and humble person
i recall reading somewhere where she
mentioned that
when she came back home from the office
she left her ceo title at the door
uh her focus was really very much just
about the family and being
a part of the family so to me that's um
that you know that's
that's the hallmark of a true truly
humble
leader last question your
bravest moments and then how do you
practice bravery
when i first returned to malaysia after
completing my masters
and it was the financial crisis at that
time in the first financial crisis in
malaysia
and i landed a job in portland in
so my responsibilities as an account
manager
was managing shipping lines
as well as freight forwarders and
logistics operators
so you can imagine john this was a field
many years ago which was traditionally
very male dominated
very few women played a key role and i
recalled
in my initial you know a couple of
months
when i started i and i had to meet these
straightforwarders and
i was initially met with a bit of a
degree of hostility i would say
but in time um you know i won their
respect because i demonstrated that
i could do the job in my next stage of
my career
in kpmg and this is something that's
kind of stuck with me
i remember that i had a couple of tough
assignments
where i had to cover africa
and in africa it was you know not cape
town or something but it was
nigeria and ghana where it was a little
rougher
and mongolia so the assignments were
fairly challenging and the clients were
very demanding
and i had to stand up for my team on
many occasions
and despite being a fairly young leader
myself at that time so i realized that
when we are clear in terms of what our
purpose is
then it is easier to you know
become brave as a leader and i think
the other thing which i realize is when
you're faced with a tough situation
you can either sort of step back um you
know and
and shrink in into yourself or that you
can step
up and lead the challenge headlong so
that's what i
typically tend to do i think it's
excellent so keep doing what you're
doing and thank you so much for your
time
you